[insects chirping and trilling]
- [tense music playing]
- [Nay Oo pants]
[yelps]
[music fades]
[exhales, sniffles]
[Nay Oo gasps]
[sniffles]
[panting]
[sirens blaring in the distance]
[foreboding music playing]
[whimpers, sobs]
[sirens fade]
[music intensifies]
THE EVIL LAWYER
[music concludes]
[dog barking]
[elevator dings]
[muffled distant chatter]
[soft pensive music playing]
[Ang] The court denied your first bail?
I wanted to see you the day I found out.
But I wasn't sure
if it'd cause you more trouble.
So you didn't visit because
you were afraid I'd be in trouble?
I'm sorry.
[keys jangling]
Come on in.
[lock clicks]
[music fades]
[door closes]
[Mek] You want coffee or anything?
[Ang] Yeah.
[coffee pouring]
Oh!
- Don't.
- [Ang] It's fine.
- Let me.
- [Ang] It's okay.
[cutlery clattering]
[Ang] When's your next court date?
I don't know. I'm waiting for an update
from my lawyer.
How's Uncle Tom?
He's fine.
But I changed my lawyer…
to Attorney Jittri.
If it wasn't for her,
I'd have died in jail by now.
- But you know that attorney--
- [Mek] I know.
And I've thought it through.
The court charged me
with premeditated murder.
They said it shows intent
that I went to Techin's house.
Why did you go to his house?
He said he'd tell me
what you refused to tell me.
The night of the party on the boat.
[soft tense music playing]
What did he tell you?
I'd rather hear it from you.
- [echoing clink]
- [music concludes]
[Ang] That night was a party
for the government coalition.
[gentle string music playing]
[Anan] Sir, this is my son, Techin.
[Techin] Hello, sir.
He's a lawyer now.
[Ang] Uncle Anan was the host
who invited everyone.
Let me know if I can help.
[Ang] I went because
I wanted the politicians
to help push the Fisheries Labor
Protection Act
that my team
and the labor coalition drafted together.
Many key government figures were there.
[dark pensive music playing]
[Ang] But Mom said
the most important person to talk to
was Suwat, the Minister of Agriculture.
If he was on board,
the bill was almost sure to pass.
I was fully prepared to present my case.
If fishing is further liberalized,
the problems for laborers will increase.
So, the party will propose
a related bill to protect the welfare…
Suwalee.
[Ang] But I soon realized
this wouldn't work.
Suwat didn't listen to me at all.
There was one waitress at the party
who Suwat seemed to have his eye on.
Suwat was acting like a typical creep.
Nothing too predatory.
Anan.
- How is it?
- Everything's fine.
[Ang] And Uncle Anan was right there.
He surely wouldn't let
anything bad happen on his boat.
[music fades]
[Ang] But later that night…
[woman screams]
[Ang] That's when I realized I was wrong.
[Techin] Please continue
to enjoy yourselves.
Someone just got drunk and fell.
It's nothing.
Go on, Top. I'll meet you at the table.
Go get the rest of the liquor. Come on.
Hey, Ang.
It's nothing.
That wasn't the sound of someone falling.
I told you, it's nothing.
[Ang] If it's nothing,
why won't you let me in?
[tense music playing]
Go upstairs.
[Techin] Go.
[clicks tongue]
You asked for it.
[tense music continues]
[Nay Oo sobbing]
[Nay Oo mutters, sobs]
Nee An.
Nee An!
What happened? Mom, let me.
[sobbing]
Please, help my sister!
Please help Nee An!
Nee An!
Ang, that's enough.
Ang!
[shrieking] No! It's not enough!
[sobs]
[in Burmese] Nee An, wake up!
Nee An, wake up!
Nee An!
[in Thai] Why aren't we heading
back to shore?
[sobbing]
[Anan] Who are you calling?
I'm calling for help.
Help with what? The girl's already dead.
[Nay Oo sobbing, muttering]
She's not dead. She could be revived
with the right equipment.
What are the chances? Almost zero.
And have you seen
who else is on this boat?
What? What do you mean?
What does it matter who's on this boat?
No one is doing anything!
Why aren't we heading to shore?
Why isn't anyone doing anything?!
[Nay Oo sobbing]
Mom.
Ang, come with me.
[Ang] Mom, where are you taking me?
Mom!
[tense music continues]
Listen to me, Ang.
No one can know about this.
What are you planning to do?
What are you and Uncle Anan
planning to do?
If anyone finds out someone died today,
everyone will be ruined.
[Ang] How could everyone be ruined?
The person who killed her
should be held responsible.
It was Suwat, wasn't it?
I saw him trying to get her drunk
at the table.
[Atchara] Ang, we can't just make
baseless accusations.
No one wanted this to happen.
But if the news gets out…
A man like Suwat won't go down alone.
Everyone in the party will be destroyed.
And what about that girl?
Is her life worth less than
the future of your party?
How can you say that? I'm a doctor.
You saw I did everything I could
to help her.
But that girl overdosed.
We have to protect what we still have.
You want me to sacrifice that girl's life
so you can continue with your work?
- [music concludes]
- She's already dead.
You didn't kill her. I didn't kill her.
But to let this ruin the lives
of everyone on this boat,
what good would that do?
But if we stay quiet,
the guilty one won't be held accountable.
Suwat won't be held
accountable. [sniffles]
[Atchara] We'll hold him accountable.
But not by sending him to prison.
Then what are you going to do?
Use your fisheries bill.
I don't think Suwat can refuse you now.
[dark somber music playing]
[Atchara] If we secure enough seats
in the next election,
at least people like Suwat
and his cronies…
won't be able to do
whatever they want anymore.
[muffled sobbing]
[Atchara] Come and work for my party, Ang.
I promise that the life of the girl
we lost today
will bring change to millions of people.
[Anan muffled] Don't you worry.
You can stop working on the boat.
You can come work at my house.
It'll be much easier.
[Ang trembling] If I could go back,
I never would have let this happen.
[music concludes]
[sniffles]
Even though I didn't kill her…
I just stood there and watched.
I just stood there and watched
her body disappear.
I've become just like them.
I've become the person I hate.
[inhales sharply]
[Mek sighs]
I'm such a piece of shit.
[sobs softly]
Ang.
[sniffles]
The night of the incident
at the golf course,
there was a female caddy from Myanmar
with me and Techin.
Here, let me help you with that.
I'm fine, sir.
[foreboding music playing]
He said that woman was the sister
of the girl who died on the boat.
And she's the one who killed Techin.
Then how did she end up at his house?
I think he was planning on killing her.
I think he wanted to make me an accomplice
so he could blackmail me
into dropping the waste plant fire case.
[sighs softly]
I shouldn't have kept it from you.
[sniffles]
[music fades]
It's okay.
We… We can't change anything now.
Right?
Come here.
[cups clink softly]
[Ang] Where is that woman now?
I don't know.
But there's no evidence
that she even exists.
So everything points back to me.
Mek, let me help you.
I'll help you find that woman.
[suspenseful music playing]
[suspenseful music continues]
[muffled heavy breathing and moans]
[both moan]
[Jittri moans loudly]
- [music builds]
- [both moaning]
- [gasps]
- [music concludes]
[both panting]
[exhales]
Ouch!
[Chanon] When will you stop being so shy?
You have too many secrets.
That's why you won't open up.
The one who's keeping me a secret…
is saying I have too many secrets?
- Seriously?
- [chuckles]
[sighs]
[Jittri] Did you get
the documents I asked for?
That bag. Hand it to me.
The witness list from Anan's side.
But there's one person
who was just added to the list.
Who is it?
This one. His name is Sorn,
a forestry officer.
He was the second person
to find Techin's body.
Anan has started sending people
to investigate you.
- You should be careful.
- [soft foreboding music playing]
Why don't you stay the night?
[Jittri] No.
I don't like having someone
sleep next to me.
Unlike you.
[door opens]
[door closes]
[grunts softly]
[music fades]
16 SOI MAHANAK 9
[Mek] Uh…
Excuse me, sir. Where is 16 Soi 9?
That way.
[indistinct chatter]
[dog barking in distance]
Uh, excuse me.
Is the Jittri Law Office around here?
Nope.
But it says right here on the card, 16/9.
I said no.
[man 1] Hey, bro. Your shoes are dope.
Where did you get them?
[tense music playing]
Thanks.
Hey, you piece of shit!
I asked you a question.
[man 2 jeers]
Not so fast, shirt guy. [laughs]
Relax. Don't be scared.
You're here for Jittri, right?
Actually, I think I have to go now.
Come on, why are you leaving so soon?
Stay with us for a bit.
We're all friends here.
- [music fades]
- Yeah, let's talk first.
Relax. Have a seat.
See? We saved you a spot.
There. All clean. Sit down.
[chuckles]
We're pretty chill in this community.
A lot of people come and go.
So I never know who means well
and who doesn't.
- [sniffs]
- [tense music resumes]
If Attorney Jittri really sent for you,
you have to tell me the password.
[music rises]
No, there isn't one. She just told me to…
Wrong. You have two more chances.
If it's cash, I don't have any.
You can take a look.
I'm not carrying any…
- Hey!
- [chair rattles]
This is your last chance, four-eyes.
What's the password?!
[music intensifies]
[man 2] Hurry up!
[music builds]
[music falls]
Ten.
Twenty.
Thirty.
Forty.
- I help the poor.
- I help the rich.
- [music stops]
- Help me, I'm stuck in an elevator.
Yeah!
♪ Ten, twenty, thirty, forty!
Come on! Ten, twenty, thirty, forty! ♪
♪ I like to swipe diamonds, swipe gems
Swipe a gold chain ♪
- ♪ I like to pull a zipper! ♪
- ♪ Ten, twenty, thirty, forty! ♪
♪ Come on! Ten, twenty, thirty, forty!
I kick it with a spin ♪
- ♪ With a curve, I do lob shots ♪
- ♪ And chip shots ♪
♪ Ten, twenty, thirty, forty!
Ten, twenty, thirty, forty ♪
♪ Fifty, sixty, seventy, eighty ♪
[man 2] Hey!
The office is this way.
We have a pretty casual style.
It's like an industrial loft. [laughs]
- [mellow music playing]
- [man 2] Come on, hurry up.
Hey, Ma.
Training for a marathon?
- Hello.
- Don't you go running?
- Where are you going?
- The market.
[man 2] To the market. To buy chicken.
She loves that stuff.
Behold! The corridor to the office.
[laughs] Come on.
Please, come in. No password required.
- [chuckles]
- Are you always this much of a dick?
Oh, that depends on the weather.
Mek, my bro.
[laughs]
Asshole. Please, come on in.
- Hello, Auntie
- [woman] Yeah.
[man 2 clears throat]
Welcome. Have you eaten yet?
[music concludes]
Here, have some fried bananas.
I just made them this morning.
[yells] Go wash your hands.
And you! How many times
have I told you to use a glass?
- [man 3] Jeez, Auntie.
- [man 1] You could've just asked nicely…
[woman] Who's going
to want to drink after you?
[man 2] What is it with you?
[overlapping chatter]
[Jittri] Oh.
So you've met them.
This is Kung, my data guy.
The other two are Meuk and Nemo.
They're Kung's assistants.
The sea creature gang?
Oh yeah? What's it to you, mammal?
You're not just my client.
You're going to help me with the cases.
So stop bickering.
It's annoying.
- [Kung] Okay.
- Where's the work I assigned?
[Kung] It's around here somewhere.
One sec.
Here. State-of-the-art technology.
[chuckles]
You've eaten, right?
It's going to be a long day.
Yes, I have. Your mother just asked.
Aunt Noi is my secretary.
Here, take a look.
Your first assignment.
[Mek] A nighttime ordination.
What's the case? A monastic offense?
[foreboding music playing]
Murder.
[crowd cheering over video]
- [crowd cheering]
- [upbeat music playing over speakers]
[Jittri] It happened six months ago
at Sri Don Saeng Temple in Pathum.
[foreboding music continues]
[Jittri] The temple held an ordination
for Nueng, the son of its lay leader.
Over a hundred guests were in attendance.
- [gunshots]
- [music stops]
[crowd screaming]
You bastard, Mai!
- [Jittri] Stop it right there.
- [echoing rumble]
[echoing ringing]
[suspenseful music playing]
[Jittri] This right here
is the prosecution's blind spot.
There's no evidence confirming
the witness actually saw Mai shoot him.
All they have is hearsay that Mai
and the deceased had bad blood.
The key witness who saw Mai
is the victim's friend, a guy named Jeng.
There were so many people there
when it happened.
Between the lights and those speakers…
If you were standing
at a slightly different angle…
you might not have seen the shooter.
If we can confuse the witness
about where they were standing,
we'll win the case.
What? Don't you get it?
If I happen to be in the same place
as my rival
at the same moment he dies,
that doesn't mean I shot him, right?
[scoffs softly]
I knew you'd use a method like this.
- [music fades]
- [echoing whoosh]
What kind of method?
The evidence in this case is weak.
You can't even see Mai's face
in the video.
Even if there were witnesses,
their testimony can't be used.
What you're doing
is confusing the court about the facts.
- This way, the guilty--
- Kung.
- [Kung] Yes?
- Right. The facts.
The facts always contain
both lies and truth.
It's the court's job to decide,
not ours. Got it?
- But--
- Look at this.
The witness list in your case.
The one highlighted in yellow.
WITNESS: SORN SAENGRUENGNOP
Sorn Saengruengnop. He's the one I--
The forestry officer
who came to the golf course
when he heard a gunshot.
And he was the second person
to find Techin's body.
- [high-pitched ringing]
- [ominous music playing]
[Jittri] That makes him
the key witness in your case.
Sorn is Mai's father. The defendant
in the ordination ceremony shooting.
So you'll help his son, and in return,
he'll change his testimony in my case?
Hmm?
No. I won't do it.
The only way to win my case
is to find that gun and the Burmese woman.
And how many days,
months or years will that take?
- Please tell me.
- [music concludes]
[sighs]
[Jittri] My source says
Anan's pressuring the court
to move up the date
for the prosecution's witness hearing.
He doesn't want us
to find evidence in time.
He wants your case closed ASAP.
Get it now?
[soft tense music playing]
What we need the most right now is time.
We'll have Sorn buy us that time.
If a key witness like him
suddenly disappears,
the court will have no choice
but to postpone the trial.
Fine. I'll agree to help Mr. Sorn's son.
But I'm not doing it your way.
I'll find my own way.
[papers rustling]
[bag rustling]
[door opens]
[door closes]
Hell yeah.
- [birds chirping]
- [music concludes]
[door clunking]
[chains jangling]
[Mek] Hello.
My dad said the new lawyer was a woman.
We're on the same team.
What happened to your face?
Ran into an old rival in here.
So the shooting at the ordination,
was it just because you didn't like him?
I may get into a lot of fights,
but I've never killed someone
over a grudge.
Are you trying to say
you weren't the one who shot him?
I shot him.
But I shot him
because of the shit he pulled.
I already told my old lawyer all this.
But he said it was useless.
Could you tell me again? I want to know.
I'm not like that other lawyer.
[sighs]
[soft tense music playing]
[exhales]
My gang and Nueng's…
we didn't have any beef before.
We just couldn't stand each other.
- We almost threw down a few times.
- [echoing whoosh]
- [crowd cheering]
- [upbeat music playing over speakers]
[overlapping chatter]
[air horn blares]
[Mai] We were just having a water fight
for Songkran.
- [glass shatters]
- [woman screams]
[Mai] Then, suddenly,
his gang came at us.
- [indistinct clamor]
- [thrilling music playing]
[Mai] I punched him,
and he fell back into an ice barrel.
He grabbed a whole block of ice
and threw it right at me.
- [woman shrieks]
- [sounds turns muffled]
[Mai] But it hit my little sister instead.
- [muffled chatter]
- [sorrowful music playing]
[EKG monitor beeping]
[muffled clamor]
[Mai] The doctor said…
my sister had a brain injury.
She was as good as dead.
But the damn cops said
they couldn't charge that bastard.
There was no weapon.
How could there be? It was a block of ice.
So that asshole only got charged…
with simple assault.
But my sister…
- she just kept getting worse…
- [EKG flatlining]
…and eventually passed away.
[muffled sobbing]
So when I found out he was pretending
to be remorseful by getting ordained,
I was even more pissed off.
When you do fucked-up shit,
you've gotta pay for it.
- [gunshot echoing]
- [music concludes]
[Mek] But the maximum penalty
for your crime
is the death penalty.
I have to pay for what I did, too.
[pensive music playing]
[sighs]
Please look after my dad for me.
His daughter's dead,
and his son's in prison.
I'm afraid he won't be able to handle it.
I will.
I'll see what I can do to help.
[phone receiver clatters]
- [chains jangling]
- [door opens]
- [door closes]
- [Noi] He killed Mai's sister first.
So Mai acted in a fit of rage.
But Nueng's side will probably deny it…
[door opens]
- Well?
- [music concludes]
Did you find a way?
Mai told me the story about his sister.
I think we can use that story
along with his confession.
The court may reduce his sentence by half.
If we're lucky, it'd just be probation.
It's his first offense.
And his motive came from
the loss of a family member.
I think the court might show mercy.
You're going to bet our client's life
on the mercy of the court?
But Mai really did kill someone.
Even with a sympathetic motive,
I think he deserves punishment.
[Jittri] You're not the judge.
It's not your place to decide
who deserves what punishment.
What about the guy who got shot?
Doesn't he deserve justice?
I can't let a murderer walk free.
How dare you call
your own client a murderer?
Let me remind you of something,
in case you forgot.
In court, you and Mai are no different.
If Mai can be a murderer, so can you.
[tense music playing]
- I didn't kill anyone.
- Those are just words. Do you have proof?
You probably think my methods are shitty.
But if the law was applied equally,
there'd be no need for people like me.
Until that day comes,
I'll defend my clients however I want,
and I won't regret it either.
Even after all you've been through,
you still don't get it.
Go back to prison, then.
Stop wasting my time.
Please continue, Aunt Noi.
[Noi] As of right now,
I'd say the witnesses are unreliable.
They were all completely drunk.
[door slams shut]
[Noi] Hmm.
Stubborn, just like his father.
If he keeps seeing the world that way,
there's no way he'll win his own case.
It won't be for long.
[music fades]
RETIREMENT PARTY FOR THE CHIEF JUSTICE
OF THE CRIMINAL COURT
- [overlapping chatter]
- [traditional folk music playing]
[guest greets]
[Padung] Anan.
[Anan] Ah. Padung.
Did you just arrive?
The traffic was terrible.
I almost told my driver to go back home.
You seem to be enjoying the show.
[Anan] "Lady Butsaba Admiring the Shrine."
I like this piece.
[Padung chuckles softly]
I can recite
volumes of Supreme Court rulings,
but when it comes to art,
music, or literature,
it all goes right over my head.
[Anan] It's from the story of Inao.
After winning the war,
Princess Butsaba comes out
to admire the beauty of the shrine.
But our Butsaba
won't be coming out to dance
anytime soon, will she?
[music concludes]
[guests applauding]
I really don't understand.
Why is a simple waste plant fire case
taking so long to wrap up?
Troublemakers just keep popping up.
Who?
[host] At this time,
I'd like to invite Judge Rit Piriyawich,
as a representative for all of us
to honor us with a few words.
Please put your hands together.
[guests applauding]
The Chief Justice taught me
from my very first day as a judge that…
being a judge
isn't just a nine-to-five job.
[foreboding music playing]
[Rit] You must also conduct yourself
with integrity at all times.
It is a difficult and heavy burden
that can lead to bias
in your rulings.
- There was a time…
- I'm doing my best to speed it up.
But Rit exercised his right
to be a co-judge.
If I rush it any more,
it'll look suspicious.
I managed to get Mek out of the way…
…no matter how immense,
we must not waver
in the face of pressure,
in the face of fear,
or in the face of our own inner biases.
We must not allow these things
to undermine us
and the sacred judicial institution
that we are sworn to uphold.
Thank you very much.
[guests applauding]
Normally, I'm a patient man.
[music concludes]
So if I feel that it's slow,
it must be taking way too long.
[tense music playing]
Don't make me warn you again.
Not everyone is as patient as I am.
[music intensifies]
[sighs]
[music concludes]
WITNESS HEARING:
THE ORDINATION CEREMONY SHOOTING CASE
[indistinct chatter]
Tell me. What's our strategy?
I'm only agreeing to do this one case.
Listen,
to win a case where we're the accused,
it's not about what we say
to convince the court.
Because being accused
is the same as being branded a bad person.
And bad people don't tell the truth.
[echoing jangle]
[intriguing music playing]
[Jittri echoing]
The only chance to win this case
is to destroy
the other side's credibility.
Make it seem as if
the prosecution is the one who's lying.
[music rises]
[Jittri] Once you make the prosecution
lose all credibility,
then no matter how firmly
the eyewitness testifies,
there's a chance the court
won't give their testimony any weight.
[music fades]
- You were close to the deceased, correct?
- Yes.
We grew up together.
Our families know each other.
On that day, did you know
that a shooting was going to happen?
How would I know that?
If I knew, would my friend be dead?
And before the incident,
did you see the defendant at the event?
[Jeng] I didn't see him.
But if I had,
I would have stomped him to death.
[lawyer clears throat]
I mean, I would have taught him a lesson.
You said you were close with the deceased.
Were you previously aware
that the deceased had conflicts
with people other than the defendant?
I wouldn't know. The conflict
I did know about was with that guy, Mai.
So you had no prior knowledge
that more than ten separate police reports
had been filed
against the deceased
for violence involving others.
- And among those cases--
- [lawyer] Pardon me, Your Honor.
I believe the deceased's conflicts
with others are irrelevant to this case.
[judge] Keep it relevant, Counselor.
[Mek] Document L.7, Your Honor.
This is where you stood
when you saw the shooting, is that right?
[Jeng] Yeah.
MAP OF THE DAY OF THE INCIDENT
Are you sure? Take a closer look.
I'm sure.
I remember a utility pole
was on my right.
I stood there with Gas and Khun.
You can go ask them.
[Mek] And this is the spot
where the defendant was standing, right?
[Jeng] Yeah, he was under the teak tree.
He was running away.
Are you sure about that?
Because it was very dark under that tree.
How could it be dark?
The whole party was lit up.
Oh, and another thing,
when that guy Mai fired…
the muzzle flash was bright.
His face was pretty damn clear.
[soft tense music playing]
But you previously gave a statement
that you turned around
after you heard the gunshot.
It went "bang," then I turned.
Then how could you have seen
the muzzle flash?
So, did you see the defendant
while he was shooting or afterwards?
I turned just before he fired the shot.
So, to be clear,
you didn't duck or even blink
like everyone else?
Then how did you still see the flash?
I've shot guns before. I'm not afraid.
Why are you asking? Seriously.
[lawyer] Objection, Your Honor.
I believe he's pressuring the witness.
[judge] Don't pressure
the witness, Counsel.
Proceed.
Yes, Your Honor.
Then could you please confirm
one more time
that the blue dot marks the spot
where you were standing?
Confirm that it matches
the blue dot on the screen.
Yeah. I was standing right there.
And do you remember
there were speakers there that night?
There was music. So yeah,
there were speakers. I remember.
[Mek] Do you remember
where they were?
I wouldn't know.
[Mek] Your Honor, I request permission
to show the witness a video clip,
to aid in his testimony.
[foreboding music playing]
[Mek] That's the spot where you said
you were standing, correct?
And that's where you said
the defendant committed the act.
Do you see the large set of speakers
blocking your line of sight?
You don't remember that at all?
They were just there, that's all.
But what I saw for sure was Mai's face.
It was so damn clear.
[Mek] This is my last question.
Did you drink any alcohol that night?
No.
I didn't drink. [sniffs]
He claims he wasn't drinking.
[Mek] No further questions.
Prosecutor, any redirect?
[lawyer] No, Your Honor.
[judge] Witness, you may step down.
[music fades]
I'd like to call my next witness.
Mr. Mana Saengsom, known as Abhinanto.
The abbot of Pa Ban Khru Temple.
[intriguing music playing]
I hereby swear before the Emerald Buddha…
- One moment, please.
- [music stops]
A monk is not required to swear an oath.
Prosecutor, you may proceed.
On the night of the incident,
where were you?
And what did you witness?
Could you please tell us?
At that time, uh…
They were holding
an ordination procession outside.
I was inside the prayer hall.
[gunshots]
[crowd screaming]
[Mana] I heard gunshots
and people screaming.
- [running footsteps]
- [suspenseful music playing]
[Mana] I saw Mai.
He ran to a motorcycle
parked next to the prayer hall.
How clearly did you see his face?
[motorcycle engine revs]
[Mana] Very clearly.
We even made eye contact
before he rode off.
I am only speaking the truth.
Lying is a sin.
That's enough, Father.
No further questions.
The defense may cross-examine.
[music fades]
You knew the deceased, is that correct?
[Mana] Yes. He was a good boy.
He could be a bit unruly at times.
But he was ordained as a novice under me
when he was a boy.
[Mek] Do you know
the boys sitting over there?
Yes, I know all of them.
They've been running around the temple
since they were children.
Some of them were even ordained.
So, I definitely know them.
Especially Jeng, Nueng, and Mai.
They were the ringleaders.
So, for me to be here as a witness…
I will speak without any bias.
[intriguing music playing]
Holding an ordination ceremony at night,
with liquor, lights and music
like a nightclub.
Is that considered normal in Buddhism?
[Mana] It may seem strange to you.
But the truth is,
some people aren't free during the day.
So they ask their relatives and friends
to come help out at night.
But inside the prayer hall,
everything followed religious tradition
without any changes.
So does that mean anyone can hold
an ordination at night?
I thought it would have to be someone
who is close to you,
or someone who donates a lot
to the temple.
That's not necessary.
One can be ordained without money.
There's no need to worry about that.
Because Buddhism is open to all.
If the poor wish to be ordained and study,
the temple will ordain them.
[music fades]
Well, Counselor?
Do you have any further questions?
[sighs]
No further questions, Your Honor.
[judge] Then let's examine
the defendant's witnesses.
So as not to waste time.
Yes, Your Honor.
However, the defense would like to submit
an additional witness list.
[tense music playing]
Objection, Your Honor.
The defense cannot submit
an additional witness list at this time.
It's a violation of trial procedure.
But I have new information, Your Honor.
These three witnesses will confirm
the defendant could not possibly have
murdered the deceased.
[crowd gasping, chattering]
[Jittri] I request permission to call
all three witnesses to the stand.
[echoing rumble]
- [door creaks]
- [footsteps echoing]
[tense dramatic music playing]
[Jittri] Mr. Somchai, the Mayor.
Mr. Sirikorn, the Chief of Forestry.
And Mr. Tawanchai, the School Director.
[music fades]
All three were with the defendant
the entire night.
And that night, the defendant
never set foot inside the temple.
[intense dramatic music playing]
False speech.
Sathu.
[music concludes]
[dark intriguing music playing]
[dark tense music playing]
[music concludes]